<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 16:28:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mavogel.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilias Client Lib</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-11-07-ilias-client-lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 16:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-11-07-ilias-client-lib/</guid>
      <description>The Java ilias client lib extraction Recently I got a request for extending the ilias-client with the ability to add a group to a course. The requestors wanted to use the client tool for this purpose, but a better approach was to slice the corresponding functions out of the existing tool and move it into a client library which could then be used by both tools.
Reason Due to this decision ilias-client-lib was born and released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From a Monolith to a microservices architecture</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-02-01-from-monolith-to-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:39:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-02-01-from-monolith-to-microservices/</guid>
      <description>This project was part of the masters course Distributed Information Systems at the University of Applied Sciences (Karlsruhe) with the task to split a monolithic web shop application running on Tomcat into microservices with the Spring Cloud Netflix stack and exchanging the authentication and authorization to OAuth2.
The final implementation can be found here.
Reason The reason why I put this project on my portfolio is that I decided to go the little extra mile with this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilias Client</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2016-10-27-ilias-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 12:32:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2016-10-27-ilias-client/</guid>
      <description>The Java ilias client ILIAS is the preferred e-learning platform at the University of Applied Sciences in Karlsruhe. In general
 ILIAS is a powerful Open Source Learning Management System for developing and realizing web-based e-learning. The software was developed to reduce the costs of using new media in education and further training and to ensure the maximum level of customer influence in the implementation of the software. ILIAS is published under the General Public Licence and free of charge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>