<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://mavogel.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 17:01:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mavogel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 01</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2019-cw-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 17:01:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2019-cw-01/</guid>
      <description>Postgres Problem with lots of partitions Gaining lots of knowledge on Postgres 10 especially about partioning, we observed a strange behavior on UPDATE and DELETE lately while the number of partitions was growing a lot &amp;gt; 1500.
To recap this is the table structure
CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS projection_table ( id varchar(200) NOT NULL, provider_id varchar(60) NOT NULL, input varchar(4096) NOT NULL, label varchar(100), modified_at timestamp NOT NULL ) PARTITION BY LIST (provider_id); Each partition has 2 more indexes which speed up the queries when the right partition was already determined:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned and taught in week 51</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-51/</guid>
      <description>Testing Yes, as I already mentioned I love tests. Tests should be treated like the production code they test, right? So They should also be refactored the same way. There should also be time for, and the business side should IMHO understand the importance of it. Sure the business value is not measurable at the moment, but it will be later. Especially when the test code has become a lot of copy-pasting around and engineers don&amp;rsquo;t feel like touching the test code anymore, because it has become kind of complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 50</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-50/</guid>
      <description>Postgres While creating a projection for a specific use-case, we faced the problem that there was no more room for optimization with indexes on the database. So we had to step back and re-think the whole data model which consisted of 4 tables each having more than 50 million rows. Until this point, we hat cheap inserts and expensive gets on the data model.
After the analysis of the data, we figured out that the approach we took, in the beginning, was a bit too naive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 49</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-49/</guid>
      <description>AWS Redshift This week was much focus on AWS Redshift:
Testing Unfortunately, it is currently not possible to mock a Redshift for testing. As we use white-box testing with Docker containers, I was looking for a container supporting DISTSTYLE, KEYSTYLE, as well as LOAD and UNLOAD. After researching there is no suitable container out there: neither docker-amazon-redshift, nor docker-pgredshift was appropriate. We thought
 adapting the SQL statement so that we could work with a Postgres container or about mocking TCP connections and faking the calls to Redshift  but could not find a solution, because we also did not want to adapt production code for testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 48</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-48/</guid>
      <description>AWS When you&amp;rsquo;re in doubt about a policy the policy simulator https://policysim.aws.amazon.com should always your first tool of choice.
Typescript When unwrapping an object in Typescript the following way, you should be sure that all properties match. If they don’t, they’re just undefinded
const { accessKey, accessKeySecret, region, bucket, endpoint } = this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 13:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Manuel Vogel. I&amp;rsquo;m striving to grow every day as a person and developer and I like doing good things and talk/write about them. (Kudos for the inspiration go to my buddy r3dsm0k3)
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m working at Stocard as a DevOps Engineer, doing awesome stuff with terraform, Docker, TypeScript and bash. In my free time, usually in the dark night hours, I maintain the terraform-provider-docker.
I love automating things because I believe we&amp;rsquo;re all smart people and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 46</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-46/</guid>
      <description>Building nodejs in Docker If you need to add keys to the keychain in a Travis build and you have problems with IPV6 (which Travis cannot handle), use the IPV4 keyservers as follows:
RUN set -ex \  &amp;amp;&amp;amp; for key in \  94AE36675C464D64BAFA68DD7434390BDBE9B9C5 \  #…. more keys... ; do \  gpg --keyserver hkp://ha.pool.sks-keyservers.net --recv-keys &amp;#34;$key&amp;#34; || \  gpg --keyserver hkp://p80.pool.sks-keyservers.net:80 --recv-keys &amp;#34;$key&amp;#34; || \  gpg --keyserver hkp://ipv4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 45</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-45/</guid>
      <description>Mocking with mock-server When you want to expose another port than 80 from the mock-server you need to change the serverPort. The Docker port mapping does not work in this case, which is strange
This works:
service-mock: image: jamesdbloom/mockserver:5.3.0 ports: - &amp;#34;82&amp;#34; entrypoint: /opt/mockserver/run_mockserver.sh -logLevel TRACE -serverPort 82 networks: test_net: aliases: - service-mock This does not work:
service-mock: image: jamesdbloom/mockserver:5.3.0 ports: - &amp;#34;82:80&amp;#34; entrypoint: /opt/mockserver/run_mockserver.sh -logLevel TRACE -serverPort 80 networks: test_net: aliases: - service-mock Furthermore, when mocking request and it is unclear why a request does not match an expectation merely turn on TRACE logging for the mockserver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that I learned in week 44</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 22:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/posts/things-that-i-learned-2018-cw-44/</guid>
      <description>npm libraries The following libraries should be used with pinned versions - restify@6.3.2 - and inversify-restify-utils@3.3.1
Not even with a micro change restify@6.3.4. It is incompatible with the inversify utils. You get a Constructor already exists error.
Semantic versioning is not always reliable! I found a repository pointing out this error as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilias Client Lib</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-11-07-ilias-client-lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 16:28:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-11-07-ilias-client-lib/</guid>
      <description>The Java ilias client lib extraction Recently I got a request for extending the ilias-client with the ability to add a group to a course. The requestors wanted to use the client tool for this purpose, but a better approach was to slice the corresponding functions out of the existing tool and move it into a client library which could then be used by both tools.
Reason Due to this decision ilias-client-lib was born and released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From a Monolith to a microservices architecture</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-02-01-from-monolith-to-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:39:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2017-02-01-from-monolith-to-microservices/</guid>
      <description>This project was part of the masters course Distributed Information Systems at the University of Applied Sciences (Karlsruhe) with the task to split a monolithic web shop application running on Tomcat into microservices with the Spring Cloud Netflix stack and exchanging the authentication and authorization to OAuth2.
The final implementation can be found here.
Reason The reason why I put this project on my portfolio is that I decided to go the little extra mile with this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilias Client</title>
      <link>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2016-10-27-ilias-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 12:32:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mavogel.github.io/projects/2016-10-27-ilias-client/</guid>
      <description>The Java ilias client ILIAS is the preferred e-learning platform at the University of Applied Sciences in Karlsruhe. In general
 ILIAS is a powerful Open Source Learning Management System for developing and realizing web-based e-learning. The software was developed to reduce the costs of using new media in education and further training and to ensure the maximum level of customer influence in the implementation of the software. ILIAS is published under the General Public Licence and free of charge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>